<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Spiritual | Andre Brutus]]></title>
  <link href="http://abrut.us/blog/categories/spiritual/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://abrut.us/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-11T00:45:24-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://abrut.us/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andre Brutus]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Job: sins from the youth]]></title>
    <link href="http://abrut.us/blog/2012/10/28/job-sins-from-the-youth/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-28T04:58:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://abrut.us/blog/2012/10/28/job-sins-from-the-youth</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><code>
Context: Job 13
</code>
When Job pleas to God, he calls to God and asks God to charge him with sinfulness if he finds any, knowing that he will be vindicated by his lack of sin:</p>

<blockquote><p>18Now that I have prepared my case, I know I will be vindicated.</p>

<p>19Can anyone bring charges against me? If so, I will be silent and die.</p></blockquote>

<p>But then, an interesting verse happens:</p>

<blockquote><p>26For you write down bitter things against me
and make me reap the sins of my youth.</p></blockquote>

<p>And this verse makes think of a question: Does God treat 'sins of the youth' any differently?
But hold on, this whole time, I believed Job to be a perfect man, God himself said in Job 1:8</p>

<blockquote><p>“Have you considered my servant Job? There is no one on earth like him; he is <strong>blameless and upright</strong>, a man who fears God and shuns evil.”</p></blockquote>

<p>And now(13 chapters later), I hear that Job had 'sins of his youth'.</p>

<p>At first, I was disappointed. But then, being like Job suddenly became more human.
If anything, this makes me believe in the power of God to forgive(and forget): Job sinned while in his youth, came to God and became <strong>blameless and upright</strong>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quote from Job 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://abrut.us/blog/2012/10/24/quote-from-job-2/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-24T23:21:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://abrut.us/blog/2012/10/24/quote-from-job-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>20“Why is light given to him who is in misery,
And life to the bitter of soul,
21 Who long for death, but it does not come,
And search for it more than hidden treasures;
22 Who rejoice exceedingly,
And are glad when they can find the grave?
23 Why is light given to a man whose way is hidden,
And whom God has hedged in?</p></blockquote>

<p>In the context of this verse, Job has now learnt about the death of his 10 sons and daughters, loss of his fortune (7k sheep,
3k camels, 500 oxen and donkeys), and is now experiencing disease(painful sores from the soles of his feet to the top of
his body). His wife told him to "Curse God and die!", and he answered by saying:</p>

<blockquote><p>Shall we indeed accept good from God, and shall we not accept adversity?</p></blockquote>

<p>Then Job speaks(Job 2), and this part intrigued me. He asks, why do people that live in absolute misery are given the gift of life
to begin with? People who live in such agony, that to die would be peace?</p>

<p>Coming from someone who just lost all that he loved and owned, and is now filled with painful sores, I understand why he would ask
such a question. However, this question (for me at least) raises more questions.</p>

<ul>
<li>What does it mean to be "hedged in by God"?</li>
</ul>


<p>This part perplexes me. Coming from the New Testament, were we see God(Jesus) as being the icon of love and care for others, I feel a little blindsided to the
fact that God 'hedges in people'. Truth of the matter is, He knows the beginning and the future, and to simplify 'Him' to my logical means of reasoning is none other than diminishing.
Job was human after all, and he himself believed he was 'hedged'. At this point, it just sounds like God places people at certain 'disadvantages'.</p>

<ul>
<li>What is the role as a Christian when encountering such agony and pain?</li>
</ul>


<p>It's a fact that there are people in this planet that are living in situations where they seek to end their misery. While Job was laying in ashes, his friends came by and did nothing for a week,
as he was deep in sorrow. They literally laid near him just to give him company for a whole week. Was it helpful?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
