<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Life | Andre Brutus]]></title>
  <link href="http://abrut.us/blog/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://abrut.us/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-11T01:41:41-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://abrut.us/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andre Brutus]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chronicles of a bittersweet travel experience]]></title>
    <link href="http://abrut.us/blog/2012/11/03/chronicles-of-a-bittersweet-travel-experience/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-03T10:30:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://abrut.us/blog/2012/11/03/chronicles-of-a-bittersweet-travel-experience</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Having but the best packing procrastination habits can be useful sometimes. When I'm about to fly somewhere, I usually find myself packing sometime between 2-4 hours before I need to leave the house, even If that happens to be at 6AM. The premise of late packing comes down to the generalization that given the lack sleep during the previous night, I would be able to knock out for longer periods of time during flight.This has worked wonderfully in the past: this time, I was in for a bittersweet treat.</p>

<p>For me to make it in time, I need to leave my apartment by 0605. Accounting for shower and last minute preparations, I set my alarm for 0515. Having followed my usual 'packing procrastination routine', I finished packing about 3AM. With about 2 hours of sleep, I am sure I can knock out for at least 3 of the 5 hours of the duration of the nonstop from SFO to CUN.</p>

<p>I make it to the airport on time: An hour and a half before my flight's scheduled departure. Attempt check in, but the machine wont scan my passport. Common occurrence, since my passport has been through the washer and dryer, and I usually just hand it over to the representative. However, fairly recently my mother noticed the wear on my passport, and the said to herself, "it looks like it needs some help". Then, my mother proceeded by wrapping clear tape to my passport as an "added layer of protection". The moment I saw my passport lined in clear scotch tape, I knew I would be in trouble. The whole "it's been washed" line wouldn't suffice no more. It's not like I can take the tape out because it would rip my passport to pieces. It's not looking good. Truth is, the ghetto looking passport worked. I went to Mexico, Honduras and Haiti with it, and although the immigration officers sometimes asked me what happened to it, they never hesitated to let me in/out.</p>

<p>Then the assistant looks at my passport and says: <code>I don't think you can go anywhere with this passport</code>. She called her representative, which said something on the lines of "have him go down to customs and if they approve of the passport, then let him go" So I wait an hour for customs to open, only to hear from the official that "they don't deal with passports" and "we don't look up information", promptly noting that "if the airline doesn't think its good, then you need to get a new passport". By now, I'm already counting on not making it to the wedding. I go upstairs, and I meet Asian lady A -- a United Representative.</p>

<p>Asian lady A looks at me, sees me scanning the passport and immediately yells at me telling me that I can't go anywhere with this passport. So, I'm left frustrated, thinking "what do you want me to do now". The worse part about it is that I'm trying to go to Mexico and I was born in Mexico. Apparently, they don't care. After hushing me out of the line, I'm just seating in frustration on top of my carry-on, wondering if there is any hope. I decided to give it another shot. I went to the next Aisle and pretended to not have dealt with a previous representative. I said to Asian Lady B: "Hey, I'm wondering if I could still make my flight, it leaves in 30 minutes".</p>

<p>Asian Lady B on the other hand, gives a damn(cares). She looks at my passport, doesn't think twice, and hustles. She types nefariously, calls several people and she is determined to get me in that flight. After about 7 minutes of attempts, she receives a call back and they tell her I couldn't make it. So she proceeds to rebook me to the flight on the next day. While she was doing that, service manager walks by and says "you weren't gonna let him go with THAT passport, were you?". Here I thought I could push my luck, but service manager makes sure that Asian Lady B types a note for the next representative, saying that I can't go anywhere with my current passport.</p>

<p>So even after interacting with Asian Lady B and getting rebooked, I'm still screwed, I can't just walk in the next day and hunt down the most nice looking representative to let me go with my ghetto passport. Service manager made sure to write down a note attached to my reservation so I'd be in trouble. Thank you, service manager. Way to give service, service manager. Truth is, I'm just trying to catch a wedding in the country of my birth. I don't see the big deal, It's not like they are not going to let me in to Mexico, and it's not like they are not going to let me back in to the US.</p>

<p>Service Manager leaves, and Asian Lady B continues her hustle. She sympathizes. She wants me to be on that weeding. Asian Lady A wanted me NOT to get in, Asian Lady B on the other hand wanted me to make it. She looks up the passport office, handwrites the information down and prints me a receipt. She tells me that "it's 8 in the morning, here's the passport office: if you take the metro there, you might just have a new passport by tomorrow".
My hopelessness was overturned, I could see the bleak light at the end of the tunnel. I smile, thank her and head over to the BART.</p>

<p>As I'm traveling in the metro, I can't help but to feel frustrated. I had two hours of sleep, should be on my way to Cancun, and who knows If I'd be able to get a passport on time for my flight tomorrow. My usual attitude of "well, sh*t happens" is now suppressed due to my lack of sleep. Then I make it to the passport office and the first thing I see is a sign in the wall that reads "BY APPOINTMENT ONLY".</p>

<p>I continue ahead, and the sign was no joke. I inquired the receptionist and she told me that they would be able to help me, only if they got through all the appointments. And I look at a room full of lines and people (typical DMV situation). This does not give me hope. I stand in a line with my belongings (two carry-ons) that is somewhat improvised for the people that don't have appointments. Needless to say, this line never moves, since they have to deal with all the other people in the room.
So I stay in line for hours. The whole time, I'm hungry, thirsty and tired. I haven't eaten anything for at least 15 hours. I can't even use the bathroom because I'm standing in line. I had two hours of sleep and no substances to alter my state of conciousness(coffee). Then the TV on the waiting room starts to play the news of Hurricane Sandy.</p>

<p>The news display stories of of a hurricane death toll that is over fifty people. People have no electricity, gas is sparse, there is long lines for basic amenities, and there is widespread destruction and damage. And here I am, thinking I have just had the most terrible day of my life. These people had lost their loved ones, their homes flooded and they are dealing with looting and the aftermath consequences of a hurricane. And here I am, seating on top of my carry-on in a well lit, air conditioned room, checking the social networks to kill time. Needless to say, hearing the news made me think of how big of a joke my "miserable" day was. And to be fair, I'm mostly the kind of person that takes things as they come, but my lack of sleep and need to move around to get a passport made things harder. But then, the news straightened me out. Not because there are people having a worse time than I was, but mostly because it can always be worse.</p>

<p>So I continued the process of renewal, and finally, they told me to come back between 3:00-4:00PM to pick up my new passport. The wait was over. I can finally go eat (and pee--lol). Having been on starvation mode for at least eight hours, I wasn't picky: I went to the Chinese restaurant across the passport office. As I walked in, I looked around and saw that there was this mother and daughter of Asian descent(estimate ages of 50, 20ish) that I had seen at the passport office. I said to myself: "I bet these people are having as equally a miserable day as I was, having just spent the past 7 hours in the passport office". So I called over the waiter, asked him that I would pay for them and he took care of it. I was thinking on the lines that it would make their day just a little bit better, because I understood their passport office pains. The daughter came over to the table and asked me if I worked at the passport office. I told her that I was just getting a passport myself. She then proceeded to tell me that her mother's mother (her grandmother) had just passed, and they were trying to expedite a passport so they could make it to the funeral. I was shocked, I didn't know what to say, and ended up telling her "I'm so sorry for your loss, and I hope this can make your day just a little bit better". She thanked me again, went back to her table, and continued eating. I, for once, ate some food.</p>

<p>If anything, I was privileged to have 'randomly' paid for their meal. Although it made me sad to hear that they were grieving, I felt good knowing that I could at least pay for their meal and make their day a little better. Call it dumb luck, synchronous destiny, or God working in mysterious ways, doesn't matter. It made my day about ten times better. I finished my food, got free dessert from the waiter, and waited in a hotel lobby until the time to retrieve my passport got there. When it did, waiting in line at the passport office  was a breeze due to new acquaintances from Los Altos (pretty girl from VMWare and nameless Mexican paisano). Line went by quick, and then I headed back home with the help of BART+Caltrain.</p>

<p>A lot of reflexion happened that day, perhaps due to the obnoxious amount of time I spent waiting in lines. I took the same flight on the next day to Cancun and missed the wedding ceremony but made it to the reception (partly, OK, mostly, because of waiting for my uncle, who was running on Haitian time). I had a good time with the multitude of family members; we even danced the Gangnam Style. I find myself writing this post looking out the window as I fly back to San Francisco, and in retrospective, I'm thankful for the "Asian Lady B"s in my life, and also, I have to give a shout out to the people that work at the passport office: they were extremely professional, helpful, and sincerely cared. Also, I have to say that I am grateful for Asian Lady A, because without her douching it up, I would not have been able to pay for the meal of the grieving family. It was a decent experience, and in my ebay terminology it was an "A++++ WOULD RECOMMEND". It's the little things after all!</p>

<p>By the way, this has got to be the longest blog post I have ever written to date.</p>

<p>PS: I made it to Hallowepay!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
